Finding Aid for the George Noel Mayhew Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
George Noel Mayhew Papers
1853-1965
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0289
16.80 linear_feet
Scope and Content Note
The Papers of George Noel Mayhew date from approximately 1853 to 1965 and document his education and career as a religious scholar and businessman. The bulk of the collection dates from the 1930’s to the 1960’s. Extensive correspondence document Mayhew’s career and his participation in the Disciples of Christ Church and his writings and business records provide insight into his many fields of interest. The papers are comprised of approximately thirteen cubic feet (40 boxes, 1 flat) of correspondence, teaching materials, Christian Church materials, and business records. The Mayhew Papers are arranged in eight series.
Correspondence
Personal Records
Education
Teaching Career
Writings
Christian Church
Hickman County, Tennessee
Business Records
Biographical Sketch
George Noel Mayhew was born February 20, 1897 on a farm near Mt. Airy, Virginia. He was one of seven children born to George Washington Mayhew and Bettie Sue Hodnett Mayhew. He attended the Renan High School and Preparatory Department of Lynchburg College from 1914 to 1918. Upon graduation he attended Lynchburg College where he graduated with an A. B. in 1922. Over the next ten years he attained a M. A. from Vanderbilt University, a B. D. from Yale University and a Ph. D. from the University of Chicago.
His specialty was the field of Oriental religions, but his interests extended from agriculture to zoology. At Yale he was one of thirty-six picked for the first post-war friendship mission to Europe. At the University of Chicago he was awarded the Bateson travel fellowship and later in life traveled widely in Latin America.
He was a state student secretary for the Y. M. C. A. in 1922 and remained strongly allied with Christian youth movements the rest of his life. Mayhew was associate minister at Vine Street Christian Church from 1923-1925 and the dean of the Disciples Foundation at Vanderbilt University from 1927-1936.
George Noel Mayhew taught at Vanderbilt from 1939 to 1950. At the School of Religion Mayhew was active in the Rural Life Institute, the Student Christian Association, and the Disciples of Christ Divinity House. At the School of Religion the style of his instruction, erudite and searching was renowned and often quoted by students.
He was a long-time member of the National Council on Religion in Higher Education, the American Association of University Professors, and the American Civil Liberties Union.
On April 21, 1934 George Noel Mayhew married Beulah McLean Leech, they had no children.
He owned and ran a number of farms, including a citrus farm in Florida where he retired to in the 1950’s. At one time he was also president of the McKibbon Universal Wrench Company. This company produced a specialized wrench used in heavy machinery, such as train couplers. The McKibbon Company sold off its assets and folded in 1940.
He died at his home in Florida on August 7, 1965.
Chronology:
February 20, 1897 Born near Mt. Airy, Virginia
1922 Received an A. B. from Lynchburg College
1922 State student secretary of Y. M. C. A. in Tennessee
1923-1925 Associate minister at Vine Street Church in Nashville, Tennessee
1926 Received a B. D. from Yale University
1927 Received an A. M. from Vanderbilt University
1927-1936 Dean of Disciples Foundation at Vanderbilt University
1927-1934 Associate Professor of Church Organization and Administration at Vanderbilt University School of Religion
1932 Received a Ph. D. from Chicago University
April 21, 1934 Marries Beulah McLean Leech
1937-1938 Professor of Comparative Religions at Vanderbilt University College of Arts and Science
1939-1950 Professor of History of Religions and Biblical Literature at Vanderbilt University School of Religion
1939 Chairman of the Faculty of the School of Religion
1946 Tours South America
1950 Teaches part-time due to heart condition
1963-1965 Professor Emeritus
August 7, 1965 Died in Florida
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1923 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1924 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - January-March 1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - April 1927 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - May 1927 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - June, September 1927 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - October 3, - October 13, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - October 14, - October 30, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - November 1927 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - December 1927 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - January 2, - January 16, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - January 21, - January 31, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - February 1, - February 17, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - February 18, - February 28, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - March 1, - March 14, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - March 15, -March 30, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - April 1928 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - May 3, - May 15, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - May 17, -May 30, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - June 1928 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - July 1928 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - August 1928 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - September 1928 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - October 1, - October 10, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - October 11, - October 31, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - November 1928 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - December 1928 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - January 1929 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - February 1, - February 8, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - February 10, February 28, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - March 1929 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - April 1929 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - May 1929 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - June 1929 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - July 1929 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - August-September 1929 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - October 1929 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - November 1929 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - December 1929 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - January 1930 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - February 1930 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - March 1930 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - April 1930 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - May 1930 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - June 1930 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - July 1930 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - August 1930 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - September 1930 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - October 1930 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - November-December 1930 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - January-March 1931 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - April-June 1931 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - July-September 1931 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - October 1931 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - November-December 1931 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - January 1932 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - February 1932 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - March-May 1932 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - June 1932 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - July-September 1932 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - October-December 1932 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - January-April 1933 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - May-June 1933 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - August-September 1933 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - October-December 1933 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - January-July 1934 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - September-October 1934 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - November-December 1934 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - January-February 1935 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - March 1935 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - April-July 1935 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - January-October 1936 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - November-December 1936 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - January-February 1937 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - March-May 1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - June-December 1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - January-March 1938 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - April-July 1938 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - August-October 1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - November-December 1938 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - January-February 1939 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - March 1939 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - April 1939 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - May-September 1939 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - October-November 1939 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - December 1939 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - January 1940 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - February-March 1940 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - April-May 1940 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - June-August 1940 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - September-December 1940 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - January-March 1941 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - April 1941 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - May-August 1941 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - September 1941 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - October 1941 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - November-December 1941 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - January 1942 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - February 1942 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - March 1942 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - April 1942 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - May 1942 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - June 1942 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - July 1942 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - August-September 1942 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - October 1942 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - November-December 1942 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - January 1943 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - February 1943 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - March 1943 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - April 1943 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - May 1943 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - June 1943 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - July-August 1943 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - September-October 1943 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - November-December 1943 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - January-February 1944 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - March-April 1944 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - May-June 1944 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - July-August 1944 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - September-December 1944 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - January-February 1945 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - March-April 1945 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - May-July 1945 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - August-October 1945 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - November-December 1945 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - January 1946 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - February 1946 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - March-April 1946 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - May 1946 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - June 1946 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - December 1946 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - January-February 1947 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - March-April 1947 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - May-December 1947 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - January-April 1948 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - May-September 1948 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - January-December 1949 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - January-August 1950 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - January-November 1951 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - March-May 1952 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - March-December 1955 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - February 1956 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - March-April 1957 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - May 1957 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - June 1957 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - September-November 1957 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - January-December 1958 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - March-October 1959 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - December 1960 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - January-July 1961 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - July 1962 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Undated, fragments (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Abarnable – Agerton (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Ainslee – Almquist (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Ambrose – Annis (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Appel – Austin (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Babb – Banks (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Barfield – Barnett (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Barnum – Bayles (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Beach – Bennett (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Benson – Bevier (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Bickley – Biehle (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Billington – Bixley (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Black – Bliss (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Bobbett – Boone (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Booth – Boyles (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Braden – Bricker (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Brier – Brooks (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Alva Ross Brown – Genevieve Brown (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - G. M. Brown – O. E. Brown (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Paul Brown – Bryant (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Buchanan – Burke (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Burnett – Bzach (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Cadman – Calvert (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Cemeron – Canon (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Capt – Carney (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Carpenter – Carr (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Carré – Cassady (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Cassetty – Cate (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Cathey – Cayce (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Chadwell – Christian (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Clagett – Cloyd (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - M. D. Clubb (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Coan – Compton (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Conley – Coppock (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Stephen J. Corey (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Cortner – Coyle (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Craig – L. W. Crawford (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Meredith P. Crawford – Critchfield (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Crocy – Crystal (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Cull – Custiss (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Dake – DeFreese (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Degenhart – Dick (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Dickson – Douglass (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Dowdell – Dysart (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Eagles – Moody Edwards (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Richard H. Edwards, January 19, 1927 – July 1, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Richard H. Edwards, August 7, 1929 – August 29, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - T. C. Edwards – Ellis (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - England – Ezell (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Club – Ferguson (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Ferre – Fly (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Fogelsong – H. R. Foster (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Oliver “Tweedy” Foster – Fox (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Fance - Funk (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Gabriel – Gilbert (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Gilham – Glaser (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Glenn – Graffis (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Graham – Gwynn (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Haden – Halliburton (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Halks – Hardin (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Hardison – H. G. Harmon (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - H. H. Harmon (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Nolan B. Harmon, Jr. – Everett Harris (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Frank W. Harris – J. E. Hart (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Oliver Hart – Hazlewood (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Head – Henson (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Herman – Hewlett (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Hibbitts – Hilgard (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Hilger – Hitti (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Hobart – Burton Hoffman (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Conrad Hoffman, Jr. – Holley (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Hollmann – Hoover (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Hopkins – Horton (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Houk – Hoye (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Hubbard – Huddleston (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Huff – Huiell (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Hull – Hundley (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Hunt – Hyndman (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Ijams – Ellis Inlow, November 28, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Ellis Inlow, December 3, 1938 – December 15, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Inman – Ismail (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Jackson – Jarman (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Jealous – Arthur Jones (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Barclay L. Jones – L. T. Jones (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - O. W. Jones – Joyner (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Kanagawa – Kershner (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Kester – Key (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Keyes – King (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Kingdon – Kirkland (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Kirkpatrick – Kolby (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Korman – Kuo (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Lacey – Lanier Company (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Lyle Lanier (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Lantz – Lazarus (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Lea – LeBaron (Box 15, Folder 17)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Lebeck – Leech (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Leftwich – Leys (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Licher – Lomax (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Long – Lyon (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Mabushen – Mansfield (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Manson – Masch (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Mason – Mays (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Arthur B. Mayhew – Edgar Mayhew (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Elizabeth Mayhew – H. C. Mayhew (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Henry Mayhew (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Isabella Mahew – Mrs. George W. Mayhew (mother) (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - McAllister – McCoy (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - McCulloch – McEuen (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - McEvers – McKissack (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - McKnight – McWane (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Mead – Meyer (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Middlebush – Miller (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Milligan – Mix (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Mobley – M. H. Montgomery (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - R. B. Montgomery (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Moody –Moreland (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Moreford – Raymond Morgan (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - William H. Morgan – David Morse (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - I. B. Morse – Mueller (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Mulenberg – Myhr (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Naff – Neel (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Neely – Nestor (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Nettlehorn – Newman (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Newton – Noh (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Robert T. Nooe (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Norman – Nutting (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Obenhaus – Owens (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Pach – Parham (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Parker – Patterson (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Paty – Payne (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Pearson – Petty (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Pfeiffer – Pickett (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Pier – Pinkerton (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Pitner – Pollack (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Pollock – David Porter (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - J. F. Porter – Powell (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Prather – Prichard (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - H. O. Pritchard, March 10, 1927 – July 22, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - H. O. Pritchard, February 10, 1930 – April 7, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - H. O. Pritchard – Hattie Pritchard (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Proctor – Pyles (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Qualls – Rash (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Ratti – Reid (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Reis – Ribble (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Rice – Rippy (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Roadruck – Carroll C. Roberts (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - David E. Robert – James K. Robinson (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - J.R. Robison – H. B. Robinson (Box 18, Folder 21)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Roche – Royar (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Ruark – Ryan (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Sadler – Salinas (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Salmon – Saxon (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Scarborough – Schisler (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Schmidt – Schuster (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Schwab – Severassee (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Shackleford – Sharp (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Sharratt – Sherwood (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Shields – Shultz (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Sikes – Singleton (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Sippel – Sly (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Small – A. C. Smith (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Alya Dean Smith (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Benjamin Smith – Joseph Smith (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Kirby Smith – William Smith (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Snipes – Spanier (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Sparkman – Spencer (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Sperry – Sprong (Box 19, Folder 19)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Staley – Stanley (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Stapel – Stem (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Stephen – Stone (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Stoney –Sturm (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Sugg – Swanson (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Swearingen – Swomley (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Takebayashi – Alva Taylor (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Betty Taylor – Testerman (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Thomas – F. Fagen Thompson (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Hugo Thompson – Tillett (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Tillman – Treadway (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Trosper – Tyner (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Underhill – Van Lear (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Vance – Vaughn (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Vause – Vorus (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Wade – J. B. Walker (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - J. E. Walker – Wallace (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Walsh – Ware (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Warkentin – Watson (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Weatherford – Webb (Box 20, Folder 20)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Weber – West (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Westbrook – Wezmar (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Whalen – B. T. White (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Edmond White – Whitwell (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Wickes – Wiley (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Wilkerson – Overton Williams (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Peyton R. Williams –Willoughby (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Allen Wilson – E.C. Wilson (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Frank T. Wilson – Sadie Mae Wilson (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Winchester – Witt (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Wolf – Woodruff (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Woodward – Wuench (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Yankee – Zondervan (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Fragments, incomplete signatures #1 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Fragments, incomplete signatures #2 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Fragments, incomplete signatures #3 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Fragments, incomplete signatures #4 (Box 21, Folder 17)
- Personal Records
  - Biographical (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Diary, reflections (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Diaries, 1917-1919 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Diaries, 1920, 1923 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Address, Date Books (4) (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Certificates and Diplomas (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Will –George Noel Mayhew (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Personal Records
  - Mayhew Family Wills, Deeds (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Mayhew Family Wills (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - G. N. Mayhew Bills and Receipts, 1921-1929 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - G. N. Mayhew Bills and Receipts, 1930-1937 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - G. N. Mayhew Bills and Receipts, 1938-1939 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - G. N. Mayhew Bills and Receipts, 1940-1949 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - G. N. Mayhew Bills and Receipts, 1950-1959 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - G. N. Mayhew Bills and Receipts, 1962-1964 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - G. N. Mayhew Bills and Receipts, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - G. N. Mayhew Insurance Records (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Personal Records
  - Travel Materials (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Travel Materials (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Travel Photographs (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Nashville Rotary Club (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Flying/Airplane Information (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Photographs (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Photographs (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Education
  - Transcripts (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Lynchburg College –Class Notes, 1922 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Lynchburg College –Laboratory Manuals (2) (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Lynchburg College –Miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Yale University – Class Notes, 1926 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Yale University –Class Notes, 1926 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Yale University –Class Notes, 1926 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Yale University –Class Notes, 1926 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Yale University –Class Notes, 1926 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Yale University –Class Notes, 1926 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Yale University –Class Notes, 1926 (Box 25, Folder 11)
- Education
  - Yale University –Class Notes, 1926 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Yale University –Miscellaneous (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Vanderbilt University –Class Notes, 1927 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Vanderbilt University –Class Notes, 1927 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Vanderbilt University –Masters’ Thesis, Holograph (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Vanderbilt University –Masters’ Thesis, Typewritten (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - University of Chicago –Class Notes, 1932 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - University of Chicago –Class Notes, 1932 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - University of Chicago –Class Notes, 1932 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - University of Chicago –Class Notes, 1932 (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Education
  - University of Chicago –Class Notes, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - University of Chicago –Class Notes, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - University of Chicago –Class Notes, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - University of Chicago –Class Notes, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - University of Chicago –Class Notes, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - University of Chicago –Class Notes, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - University of Chicago –Class Notes, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - University of Chicago –Dissertation, typewritten (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - University of Chicago –Miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 9)
- Teaching Career
  - Vanderbilt University –Lecture Notes (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Vanderbilt University –Lecture Notes (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Vanderbilt University –Lecture Notes (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Vanderbilt University –Lecture Notes (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Vanderbilt University –Lecture Notes (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Vanderbilt University –Lecture Notes (Box 28, Folder 6)